Guide to the Duke Family papers on the Duke Farms residence, 1859-2004 and undated RL.01437
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Administrative Records, 1859-2004 and undated
  - Inventory of wines, undated (Box 261, Folder 12)
  - Paintings prices and picture, undated (Box 261, Folder 13)
  - Recipes that were copied for Miss Duke, some on Duke Farms letterhead, some in Doris Duke's handwriting, undated (1 of 2) (Box 261, Folder 14)
  - Recipes that were copied for Miss Duke, some on Duke Farms letterhead, some in Doris Duke's handwriting, undated (2 of 2) (Box 261, Folder 15)
  - Somerville inventory, missing from inventory, undated (Box 261, Folder 16)
  - Telephone lists and emergency lists, undated (Box 261, Folder 17)
  - Various furniture and equipment inventories with handwritten notes from Doris Duke, undated (Box 261, Folder 18)
  - Well locations and water lines at Duke Farms, undated (Box 261, Folder 19)
  - Duke Farms Dairy and Field Crops, Statement of Cash Receipts and Operating Expenses, 1983 Jan 31 (Box 261, Folder 20)
  - East Duke's Parkway overr Duke's Bridge Replacement, Panels 184A, 184B, UE184C, UE184D, UE184E and administrative just compensation determination, 1993 (Box 261, Folder 21)
  - Letter and transparency regarding the possible purchase of Indo-Portuguese furniture from Goa, 1977 Aug 2 (Box 263, Folder 1)
  - Architectural drawings for the Duke Farms Foundation by National Greenhouse Co., 1999 Apr (Box 263, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda and correspondence describing various activities and repairs at Duke Farms, 1978-1992 (1 of 2) (Box 264, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda and correspondence describing various activities and repairs at Duke Farms, 1978-1992 (2 of 2) (Box 264, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda regarding Turkish Room restoration work. Includes color photographs of doors shipped to Duke Farms, 1983 (Box 264, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda regarding repair work at Duke Farms. Includes information about New Zealand dairy farming, 1978 (Box 264, Folder 4)
  - Photocopies of articles about Duke Farms, written in 1914, undated (Box 264, Folder 5)
  - Duke Estate-compilation of Trees and Plants, 1977 Jan (Box 264, Folder 6)
  - Memoranda describing weekly activities at Duke Farms, 1977-1979 (Box 264, Folder 7)
- Duke Business Office Records, 1954-1990
  The Duke Business Office managed the daily operations of Duke Farms, focusing on areas such as security, licensing, accounting and finance controls and reports, personnel, the construction and renovations of structures at Duke Farms, and equipment and vehicle purchases. Originally based in New York, it moved from New York City to Duke Farms in 1975. Materials in this series include applications for licenses and loans, tax assessments and returns, invoices and vouchers for maintenance repairs, job descriptions, and correspondence and memoranda related to various security matters at Duke Farms. Of particular interest are the security reports to Doris Duke, which includes reports on the status of Miss Duke's dogs, employee and visitors to Duke Farms and reporting suspicious and routine activities around the estate.
  The materials in this series are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - 178 E. 72nd Street House. 1979–1980 (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - Aeronautics, Application renewals, heliport, special notices, N.J. DOT, other.1962–1963, 1976–1991 (Box 205, Folder 2)
  - ACME Electrical Supply Co, Inc. 1984 (Box 205, Folder 3)
  - Agway Oil purchases, houses at Duke Farms. 1978–1984 (Box 205, Folder 4)
  - Alcohol-Gasohol. 1979–1980 (1 of 2) (Box 205, Folder 5)
  - Alcohol-Gasohol. 1979–1980 (2 of 2) (Box 205, Folder 6)
  - Alcohol Production (Gasohol), Correspondence. 1979–1981 (Box 205, Folder 7)
  - Alcohol Production (Gasohol), Memoranda and Notes. 1979–1980 (Box 205, Folder 8)
  - Alcohol Production (Gasohol), Plans for Mother’s Still. c. 1980 (Box 205, Folder 9)
  - Alcohol Production (Gasohol), Tax Information. 1979–1988 (Box 206, Folder 1)
  - Alcohol Production (Gasohol), U.S. Treasury Dept., Bureau of Alcohol, Federal Register. 1980 (Box 206, Folder 2)
  - Alcohol Production (Gasohol), U.S. Treasury Dept., Bureau of Alcohol, Manufacturers Brochures. 1980 (Box 206, Folder 3)
  - Alcohol Production (Gasohol), U.S. Treasury Dept., Bureau of Alcohol Permits, Tax Return, and Production. 1980 (Box 206, Folder 4)
  - American Surgical Supplies, Inc. 1984 (Box 206, Folder 5)
  - The Animal Medical Center Space study, donations to The A.M.C. 1972–1973 (Box 206, Folder 6)
  - Aqua Fire Energy Corp. 1985 (Box 206, Folder 7)
  - AT&T Contract. 1981–1986 (Box 206, Folder 8)
  - Barn Jump Information. 1989 (Box 207, Folder 1)
  - Becton Dickinson. 1985 (Box 207, Folder 2)
  - Cargill. 1983–1984 (Box 207, Folder 3)
  - Carolyn Horton & Associates, Inc. 1983 (Box 207, Folder 4)
  - Carpeting (Allen Carpets). 1975 (Box 207, Folder 5)
  - Capitol Electric Equipment Co. 1979–1985 (Box 207, Folder 6)
  - Charles Meyn, Art Jarvela. 1979, 1983–1984 (Box 207, Folder 7)
  - Chicon, Christopher. 1984 (Box 207, Folder 8)
  - Chemical Bank. 1989 (Box 207, Folder 9)
  - Chemical Bank, Draft A/C. 1987 (Box 207, Folder 10)
  - Chemical Bank, General Disb. 1988 (Box 207, Folder 11)
  - Chemical Bank – Payroll (DF). 1987 (Box 208, Folder 1)
  - Chemical Bank – Payroll (DF). 1988 (Box 208, Folder 2)
  - Commerce Clearing House, Inc. 1976 (Box 208, Folder 3)
  - Computerland of Somerville. 1984 (Box 208, Folder 4)
  - Cows. 1988 (Box 208, Folder 5)
  - Cow and Calf Inventory. 1987–1990 (Box 208, Folder 6)
  - Cruiser Construction – Consolidated Shipbuilding Corp. 1987 (Box 208, Folder 7)
  - Cummins – Perforator. 1988 (Box 208, Folder 8)
  - Dairylea Cooperative, Inc. 1973, 1978–1979, 1984 (Box 209, Folder 1)
  - David Berdon & Co. I & II. 1974–1984 (1 of 2) (Box 209, Folder 2)
  - David Berdon & Co. I & II. 1974–1984 (2 of 2) (Box 209, Folder 3)
  - D.D.V.G. Corporation. 1985 (Box 209, Folder 4)
  - Department of the Treasury. 1985 (Box 209, Folder 5)
  - DOMS Import Car Center, Inc. February 23, 1984 (Box 209, Folder 6)
  - Duke Business Office, Memos. 1976–1981 (Box 209, Folder 7)
  - Duke Business Office, Petty Cash Reconciliation. 1979–1983 (Box 209, Folder 8)
  - Duke Power Company. 1982–1983 (Box 209, Folder 9)
  - Dun & Bradstreet. 1978, 1980–1982, 1984 (Box 209, Folder 10)
  - Eaton, Van Winkle & Greenspoon Invoices. 1974–1983 (Box 209, Folder 11)
  - Edward Ehrbar, Inc. (includes Color Tile application for credit). 1984 (Box 209, Folder 12)
  - Eichman, Susan M. 1984–1985 (Box 209, Folder 13)
  - Farm – Somerville. 1985, 1989 (Box 210, Folder 1)
  - Farm & Family Center. c. 1984 (Box 210, Folder 2)
  - Farm Information (inventories, depreciation schedules). 1989–1990 (Box 210, Folder 3)
  - Farmland Assessment, Application for. 1988–1989 (Box 210, Folder 4)
  - Farmland Assessment, Application for. 1990 (Box 210, Folder 5)
  - Farm Land Preservation (copies, correspondence, clippings). 1986–1987 (Box 210, Folder 6)
  - Farm Land Preservation (correspondence, clippings). 1986–1987 (Box 210, Folder 7)
  - Farm Land Preservation (copies, correspondence). 1987 (Box 210, Folder 8)
  - Farm Land Preservation (correspondence). 1987–1988 (Box 210, Folder 9)
  - Field crop plan (Duke Farms). 1989 (Box 210, Folder 10)
  - Frank Verkey Plumbing & Heating. 1982 (Box 210, Folder 11)
  - Franklin Warehouse & Movers, Inc. 1975 (Box 210, Folder 12)
  - G&G Bearing Inc. 1983 (Box 211, Folder 1)
  - Gelson’s Markets. 1984 (Box 211, Folder 2)
  - Golden Equipment Company, Inc. 1978 (Box 211, Folder 3)
  - Graphic Sciences (Dex Machine) – Burroughs Corp. 1979–1983 (Box 211, Folder 4)
  - Great A&P Tea Company, Inc., The. 1984 (Box 211, Folder 5)
  - Greenspoon. 1986 (Box 211, Folder 6)
  - Grutman, Miller & Greenspoon. 1982 (Box 211, Folder 7)
  - Grutman, Miller & Greenspoon. 1984 (Box 211, Folder 8)
  - Guardian Garage. 1977–1982 (Box 211, Folder 9)
  - Hannah Veary, purchase of home to be repaid to Miss Duke. 1964 (Box 211, Folder 10)
  - Herzog, Edwin H. 1983–1984 (Box 211, Folder 11)
  - Hewlett-Packard Company (Note inside 312,000 shares held December 27, 1985). 1985 (Box 211, Folder 12)
  - Homestead Tax Rebate claims. 1976–1989 (Box 211, Folder 13)
  - I.B.M. System 34 – Computer Information & Correspondence. 1983–1984 (Box 211, Folder 14)
  - Indian Textile Company Private Ltd., The. 1976–1977 (Box 211, Folder 15)
  - J&C White Truck Center. 1981 (Box 211, Folder 16)
  - J.S. Amerman, undated (Box 211, Folder 17)
  - J. Schull – Insurance Correspondence. 1984 (Box 211, Folder 18)
  - Jaeger Lumber. c. 1980s (Box 211, Folder 19)
  - Johnstone Supply. September 7, 1984 (Box 211, Folder 20)
  - Kelley Blue Book. 1985 (Box 211, Folder 21)
  - Kelp-Ethel Toburen. 1969–1973 (Box 211, Folder 22)
  - Leonville Prospect, Louisiana – Report, possible purchase. 1967 (Box 211, Folder 23)
  - Liability Policies. 1980 (Box 211, Folder 24)
  - Lucky Southern Food Division. January 1985 (Box 211, Folder 25)
  - Middlesex–Somerset–Mercer Regional Study Council, Inc. 1978–1979 (Box 212, Folder 1)
  - Morgan Guaranty Payroll Account Analysis, 1976 (Box 212, Folder 2)
  - N.J. Water Supply Authority. 1978–1982 (1 of 2) (Box 212, Folder 3)
  - N.J. Water Supply Authority. 1978–1982 (2 of 2) (Box 212, Folder 4)
  - N.J. Water Supply Authority. January 1983–June 1983 (Box 212, Folder 5)
  - N.J. Water Supply Authority. July 1983–December 1983 (Box 212, Folder 6)
  - N.J. Water Supply Authority. 1985–1986 (Box 212, Folder 7)
  - N.L.T. – American General Merger. 1982 (Box 213, Folder 1)
  - Nassau Oil. 1984 (Box 213, Folder 2)
  - Near East Dance Foundation, Inc. (miscellaneous). 1972 (Box 213, Folder 3)
  - New England Engine Corp. 1985 (Box 213, Folder 4)
  - Newport Hardware. 1985 (Box 213, Folder 5)
  - North Carolina Museum of Art (tapestries – Flemish/French Regency). 1954–1958, 1980 (Box 213, Folder 6)
  - Olivetti Corporation of America. 1976–1977 (Box 213, Folder 7)
  - Pargas Equipment Lease. January 17, 1983 (Box 213, Folder 8)
  - Park Department weekly reports. 1975–1980 (Box 213, Folder 9)
  - Payroll. April 1974–September 1975 (1 of 2) (Box 213, Folder 10)
  - Payroll. April 1974–September 1975 (2 of 2) (Box 213, Folder 11)
  - Pension Plan for Duke Employees. 1984 (Box 214, Folder 1)
  - Personal Property Taxes. 1976 (Box 214, Folder 2)
  - Personnel (Farms Staff). 1980 (Box 214, Folder 3)
  - Personnel Policy Service, Inc. 1985 (Box 214, Folder 4)
  - Price Waterhouse & Company. 1978–1982 (Box 214, Folder 5)
  - Price Waterhouse & Company. 1973–1978 (1 of 2) (Box 214, Folder 6)
  - Price Waterhouse & Company. 1973–1978 (2 of 2) (Box 214, Folder 7)
  - Public Service Electric & Gas. 1973–1975, 1983–1985 (Box 214, Folder 8)
  - Radio Station. 1974–1979 (Box 215, Folder 1)
  - Real Estate. 1984–1985 (Box 215, Folder 2)
  - Rice Production. 1977 (Box 215, Folder 3)
  - Richard Ryshavy. 1979–1981 (Box 215, Folder 4)
  - Riding Arena. 1989 (Box 215, Folder 5)
  - Road Maintenance. 1976–1978 (Box 215, Folder 6)
  - Security, Duke Farms. 1975 (Box 215, Folder 7)
  - Security, Duke Farms. 1979 (Box 215, Folder 8)
  - Security, Duke Farms. 1980 (Box 215, Folder 9)
  - Security, Duke Farms. 1980–1981 (Box 215, Folder 10)
  - Security, Fence alarms, Duke Farms. 1977–1980 (Box 215, Folder 11)
  - Schedule F (Form 1040). 1980 (Box 215, Folder 12)
  - Sculptor’s Studio. 1977 (Box 215, Folder 13)
  - Soil Conservation Program. 1977 (Box 215, Folder 14)
  - Somerset County Agreement to Convey Lands (easements and parcels). 1981 (Box 215, Folder 15)
  - Somerset County Board of Agriculture. 1983 (Box 215, Folder 16)
  - Somerset County Clinical Laboratory – Lab Tests. 1979–1985 (Box 215, Folder 17)
  - Somerset County Mosquito Extermination Commission. 1975 (Box 215, Folder 18)
  - Somerset Trust – The A.M.C. Escrow a/c GL. 1984–1987 (Box 215, Folder 19)
  - Somerset Trust Co. 1987 (Box 215, Folder 20)
  - Somerset Trust Co. Regular (024125; minimum – $20K). 1989 (Box 215, Folder 21)
  - South Branch Watershed Association. 1973–1974 (Box 215, Folder 22)
  - Synthatron Corporation – Hillsborough. 1979–1981 (Box 216, Folder 1)
  - Systems & Procedures (DF). 1970–1980 (Box 216, Folder 2)
  - Systems & Procedures (DF). 1973–1975, 1983 (Box 216, Folder 3)
  - T. Rowe Price Association, Inc. 1973–1974 (Box 216, Folder 4)
  - Tax Assessments and Tax Returns. 1975–1980 (Box 216, Folder 5)
  - Terminex Pest Control. 1980 (Box 216, Folder 6)
  - Touche Ross & Co. – Personnel Mgmt. Program. 1982–1984 (Box 216, Folder 7)
  - United Supply Company. 1984 (Box 216, Folder 8)
  - Van Doren Oil Company. 1974–1979 (Box 216, Folder 9)
  - Waco Sales – Care Free Water Conditioners. 1984 (Box 217, Folder 1)
  - Wage Rate Survey, regarding Agricultural Workers. 1974–1976 (Box 217, Folder 2)
  - Walter Plumbing, Inc. (repair of fountains in front of residence). 1984 (Box 217, Folder 3)
  - Waste Disposal. 1980 (Box 217, Folder 4)
  - Water, Septic Tanks, etc. (included document, “Water-Residence”). 1970–1971, 1979–1981 (Box 217, Folder 5)
  - Weekly Reports. 1977 (Box 217, Folder 6)
  - Weekly Reports (F. Kayser to Miss Duke). 1977-1978, 1981 (Box 217, Folder 7)
  - Weekly Reports (E. Crotty to Miss Duke). 1983 (Box 217, Folder 8)
  - Williams Pest Control, Inc. 1980 (Box 217, Folder 9)
  - Yacht Charter (Rossellini). 1979 (Box 217, Folder 10)
  - Zoning – Board of Adjustments. 1979–1984 (Box 217, Folder 11)
  - All Cities Uniform Co. regarding SEACC Security Force Uniforms, 1972 (Box 218, Folder 1)
  - Boy Scouts waiver of liability, 1974-1975 (Box 218, Folder 2)
  - Boyd Associates, 1974 (Box 218, Folder 3)
  - Codes and Maps, undated (Box 218, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and memoranda related to various security matters at Duke Farms, 1973-1974 (Box 218, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence to Mr. Greenspoon regarding security matters, 1974 (Box 218, Folder 6)
  - Dictaphone, 1974 (Box 218, Folder 7)
  - Dog Patrol, 1973-1975 (Box 218, Folder 8)
  - Dogs - medical records and progress reports, 1973-1974 (Box 218, Folder 9)
  - DBO Manager's Meeting Minutes, 1993 Apr-Sep (Box 218, Folder 10)
  - Duke Farms Heliport Certificate of License, 1974-1975 (Box 218, Folder 11)
  - Duke Farms Memorandums, 1983 Jan-Dec (Box 218, Folder 12)
  - Employee & Visitor Records, 1983 Aug-Dec (Box 218, Folder 13)
  - Fire Procedures, 1973-1974 (Box 219, Folder 1)
  - Gasoline, 1974 (Box 219, Folder 2)
  - Guard Force Schedules, 1972-1973 (Box 219, Folder 3)
  - Horse Patrol, 1974 (Box 219, Folder 4)
  - Horse Training Manuals, 1974 (Box 219, Folder 5)
  - Industrial Photo Products, 1974 (Box 219, Folder 6)
  - Issco Corporation, 1974 (Box 219, Folder 7)
  - Jeeps, 1974-1976 (Box 219, Folder 8)
  - Knapp Radio, 1974 (Box 219, Folder 9)
  - Memorada and correspondence related to various business activities at Duke Farm, 1968-1977, 1992-1993 (Box 219, Folder 10)
  - Meyner, Landis & Verdon - New Jersey Licensing Statute, 1974 (Box 219, Folder 11)
  - Motorola - proposal for radio communication system and related correspondence, 1974-1980 (Box 219, Folder 12)
  - Motorola Requisitions, 1974-1978 (Box 219, Folder 13)
  - Moving of main gate, 1974 (Box 219, Folder 14)
  - Nagra Magnetic Recorders, Inc., 1973-1974 (Box 219, Folder 15)
  - N.J. Dept. of Agriculture, 1974 (Box 220, Folder 1)
  - N.J. Fish and Game Laws, 1970-1974 (Box 220, Folder 2)
  - Pagers Radio, 1970-1974 (Box 220, Folder 3)
  - Pool waiver of liability, undated (Box 220, Folder 4)
  - Polaroid ID System, 1974 (Box 220, Folder 5)
  - Professional Photography, 1974 (Box 220, Folder 6)
  - Radio, 1974 (Box 220, Folder 7)
  - Radio Licenses, 1958-1980 (Box 220, Folder 8)
  - Ray's Sports Shop, 1974 (Box 220, Folder 9)
  - Samoth Corp. regarding fuel converter, 1975 (Box 220, Folder 10)
  - SEACC receipt for metal window guards, 1972 (Box 220, Folder 11)
  - Somerset Comm, 1974 (Box 220, Folder 12)
  - South Branch Watershed Assoc., 1974 (Box 220, Folder 13)
  - State vs. Joseph A. Holoman, 1974 (Box 220, Folder 14)
  - Switchboard, 1973-1974 (Box 220, Folder 15)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Jan (Box 220, Folder 16)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Feb (Box 220, Folder 17)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Mar (Box 220, Folder 18)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Apr (Box 220, Folder 19)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 May (Box 220, Folder 20)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Jun (Box 220, Folder 21)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Jul (Box 220, Folder 22)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Aug (Box 221, Folder 1)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Sep (Box 221, Folder 2)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Oct (Box 221, Folder 3)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Nov (Box 221, Folder 4)
  - Time Clock Tape, 1984 Dec (Box 221, Folder 5)
  - Trespassing Report - "A", 1977-1989 (Box 221, Folder 6)
  - Trespassing Report - "B", 1977-1986 (Box 221, Folder 7)
  - Trespassing Report - "C", 1974-1986 (Box 221, Folder 8)
  - Trespassing Report - "D", 1975-1985 (Box 221, Folder 9)
  - Trespassing Report - "E", 1975-1984 (Box 222, Folder 1)
  - Trespassing Report - "F", 1976-1984 (Box 222, Folder 2)
  - Trespassing Reports, 1974 (Box 222, Folder 3)
  - Ultron Security Services, 1969 (Box 222, Folder 4)
  - Vehicles, 1970-1975 (Box 222, Folder 5)
  - Volkswagen, undated (Box 222, Folder 6)
  - Warren Township Police Department General Duty Manual and Forms, 1973 (Box 222, Folder 7)
  - Weekly Security Reports, 1983 Jan-Dec (Box 222, Folder 8)
  - Weekly Schedules, 1983 Jan-Dec (Box 222, Folder 9)
  - Weekly Time Reports, 1983 Jan-Dec (Box 222, Folder 10)
  - Whittacker Assoc., 1978 (Box 222, Folder 11)
- Duke Farms Main Residence Records, 1908-1994 and undated
  Both topics and types of materials vary widely in this series, however all primarily document administrative matters in the running of the Main Residence at Duke Farms. Materials include work orders and estimates for new construction and repairs to the residence, receipts and invoices for the purchase of furniture and art objects, fabric samples for draperies, statements of operations for the Main Residence, and weekly updates to Doris Duke on the daily activities at the residence. Also included are inventories of furniture, fixtures, art, wine, and a photographic inventory of jewelry.
  The materials in this series are arranged loosely in chronological order.
  - Memorandum regarding cleaning in the Main Residence. n.d. (Box 223, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and telegrams regarding jade purchases from E. A. Punnett, Peking, China. 1935–1939 (Box 223, Folder 2)
  - Letters and notes originally located in desk drawer of the Library. c. 1940 (Box 223, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda relating to upholstery repairs. 1966, 1989 (Box 223, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and memoranda relating to daily, administrative matters including repairs, automobiles, and other maintenance work. 1973–1985 (Box 223, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and related materials concerning the installation of the Portasoft water softener at the Main Residence as well as other softeners. 1980–1982 (Box 223, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and memoranda relating to the replacement of coils in the Fur Vault and Wine Cellar. 1983 (Box 223, Folder 7)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning book binding and repairs of books located at the Main Residence. 1983–1991 (Box 223, Folder 8)
  - Instructions for installing window shades in Theater. 1984 (Box 223, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and memoranda relating to installation of new refrigeration equipment in the Fur Vault and maintenance of Vault. 1986 (Box 223, Folder 10)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning the search for rare and out of print books for the Library in the Main Residence. 1986–1988 (Box 223, Folder 11)
  - Memoranda relating to the replacement and repair of screens in the Main Residence. 1987 (Box 223, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence and related materials concerning the cleaning and restoring of rugs and carpets belonging to Doris Duke. Work completed by Costikyan, Ltd. 1987–1990 (Box 223, Folder 13)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning repairs to rugs by Costikyan, Ltd. 1988–1991 (Box 223, Folder 14)
  - Letter in regards to wallpaper hanging, Second Floor Hallway, Main Residence. 1989 (Box 223, Folder 15)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning the replacement and repair of lamp shades at the Main Residence. 1989 (Box 223, Folder 16)
  - Memoranda relating to the framing of select paintings at Lowy, N.Y.C. 1989 (Box 223, Folder 17)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning the ordering of linens. 1989–1990 (Box 223, Folder 18)
  - Notes on buying of chocolate from Cloud Nine Chocolate for use in cooking. c. 1990 (Box 223, Folder 19)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning piano tuning. 1990 (Box 223, Folder 20)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning the reupholstery of two couches in Palm Room. 1990–1991 (Box 223, Folder 21)
  - Memoranda relating to the repair of the Palm Room sofas. 1990–1991 (Box 223, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence relating to solicitation by David A. Schorsch, Inc. to Doris Duke for the purchase of furniture. 1991 (Box 223, Folder 23)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning work performed at the Main Residence by Artistic Lighting, Inc. 1991 (Box 223, Folder 24)
  - Memoranda relating to the installation of fabric as lining for the jade cabinets. 1991 (Box 224, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning administrative matters in the running of the Main Residence, Duke Farms. 1991–1992 (Box 224, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning the restoration of rugs by Costikyan, Ltd. for rugs at the Main Residence. 1991–1992 (Box 224, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning personal matters of certain employees, including Cupie Singh, Main Residence Manager, as well as other daily activities at the Main Residence. Includes information on the dogs. 1991–1997 (Box 224, Folder 4)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning the purchase of a rotisserie oven at the Main Residence. 1992 (Box 224, Folder 5)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning the purchase of fabric from Brunschwig & Fils for the Blue Room at the Main Residence. 1992 (Box 224, Folder 6)
  - Memoranda to B. Lafferty regarding the moving of the satellite from the Pine Room to the Staff Dining Room. 1993 (Box 224, Folder 7)
  - Request form for work project for new Foyer curtains, Main Residence. 1994 (Box 224, Folder 8)
  - Notes and photocopies relating to the Hoppner painting, “Charles Oldfield Bowles.” c. 1995 (Box 224, Folder 9)
  - Memoranda and related materials concerning the purchase of a custom traverse rod system for the Palm Room. 1995 (Box 224, Folder 10)
  - Estimates and correspondence mainly concerning improvements to the main residence. Kendall, Taylor & Co. handled arrangements with companies. File also includes a proposal for the greenhouse (Lord & Burnham) and notes for equipment for the Coach Barn and electrical plant. 1908–1915 (Box 224, Folder 11)
  - Invoices (copies) of purchases mainly made for the Main Residence. 1930–1958 (Box 224, Folder 12)
  - Receipt for plumbing and heating work performed on the Tennis Court as arranged by James O’Connor for Nanaline Duke. 1933 (Box 224, Folder 13)
  - Invoices and receipts for professional services rendered in connection with the erection and completion of the Tennis Court Building. 1933, 1966 (Box 224, Folder 14)
  - Invoices and related correspondence concerning Doris Duke Cromwell’s account with McMillen, Inc. 1935–1942 (Box 224, Folder 15)
  - Invoices and bills for antiques, various boxes, chests, tables, wallets, candelabra, and jade pieces. 1935–1965 (Box 224, Folder 16)
  - Invoices, vouchers and related materials concerning Doris Duke’s purchases from H. Katakawa and L. Alavoine & Co. for interior design work at the Main Residence. 1936, 1938 (Box 224, Folder 17)